Oleg Ermakov

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ermakovov Email: oleg.v.ermakoff@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/ermakovov

## About Me

Creative, reliable, and passionate Senior Full Stack Engineer with 5.5 years of experience in developing, maintaining, and supporting Frontend and Backend code. Experienced in problem-solving and decision-making. Eager to develop my technical skills as a Frontend Engineer with a strong team. Able to work as a part of a team, adapt quickly, and take on new tasks

## SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Ruby, SQL, Python, Go
- Technologies: React, Docker, HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Kafka, Git, Ansible

## EXPERIENCE

• DinoLab Tbilisi

Senior Full Stack Engineer

Aug 2023 - Present

JS/TS. React, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Roda, Go. Python, Docker, Kafka, PostgreSQL, Git, HTML, CSS

DinoLab is an educational startup offering an interactive platform for students, parents, and teachers. The platform provides customized online courses in various school subjects. DinoLab helps users develop skills applicable to academics, everyday life, and future careers

- o Implemented user action data transmission to Google Analytics, unlocking new business insights into user behavior analysis
- Launched a new mathematics course, increasing revenue by 20% and retention rate by 10%. Led frontend and backend adaptation to microservices architecture and developed the process for translating the course into English
- o Configured an additional stage server within a microservices architecture, resulting in reduced Time to Market, enhanced testing quality, and streamlined QA workflows
- Led the development of integration with our EduTech partner, including user registration via SAML protocol and bi-directional data exchange. This resulted in the successful launch of the integration's initial version and comprehensive documentation for ongoing development

Uchi.Doma Moscow and Tbilisi Senior Full Stack Engineer Aug 2020 - Aug 2023

JS/TS, React, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Docker, Ansible, PostgreSQL, Git, HTML, CSS

Uchi.Doma is an online school that provides high-quality teaching materials, a unique educational platform, and qualified tutors for learning different school subjects

- Refactored the entire codebase to integrate multi-subject functionality on our platform, resulting in a remarkable 300% increase in revenue
- o Developed an innovative service for daily database dumping and anonymization in production, reducing database dumping time from 60 to 15 minutes. This initiative not only optimized operations but also elevated our team's data security measures to the next level
- Developed engaging educational games to complement our coding course curriculum, leading to a remarkable 25% increase in student retention rate and a 30% surge in course revenue
- Optimized the Docker image build process for our application by refactoring the Dockerfile, which not only accelerated the build time but also contributed to reducing Time to Market
- Established a new testing server for our QA team, cutting testing time from 30 to 15 minutes. This initiative has empowered the team with greater flexibility and contributed to reducing Time to Market
- Implemented a new design for the client's personal account, enhancing interface responsiveness and user experience. The redesign was met with positive feedback from users and contributed to a more seamless user experience

• Awatera Moscow
Full Stack Engineer Oct 2018 - Aug 2020

Full Stack Engineer

JS, React, OpenUI5, Node.js, Loopback, MongoDB, Git

Awatera is a leading linguistic service and technology provider in the CIS countries. Our internal project, the Translation Management System (TMS), equips our managers with specialized tools to offer competitive pricing for text and voice translations

- Implemented modern React.js as a base UI library on the Frontend, replacing legacy code. This initiative resulted
  in a smoother user experience, enhanced application performance, and laid a solid foundation for future scalability
  and development
- Mentored junior developers, facilitating the seamless transition of 3 interns to full-time roles, strengthening the R&D team
- Implemented pair programming techniques within the R&D team, resulting in accelerated feature development, improved code quality, and effective knowledge sharing
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines, significantly reducing code release time and enhancing the efficiency of development cycles
- Reduced server response time by launching second Backend server and fine-tuning nginx balancer

## **EDUCATION**

• Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology
Bachelor of Applied Mathematics and Physics

Moscow

Sep. 2013 - Jul. 2019